

Seoul, Republic of Korea

🛘 (+82) 10-3125-7712 | 🗷 achromatically@naver.com | 🌴 shinhyeokoh.github.io | 🖸 shinhyeokoh | 🛅 shinhyeok-oh-5082b51a8

Summary

I obtained a master's degree in computer and communications engineering from the Kangwon National University, under the guidance of Prof. Harksoo Kim. I am currently working at Riiid as Research Scientist (NLP). I enjoy discussing topics related to transfer learning. I find pleasure in exploring ways, such as self-supervised learning, domain adaptation, and multimodality, to extract value from previously unutilized something.

Education

Kangwon National University

M.S. IN DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING, GPA 4.31 / 4.5

Chuncheon, Republic of Korea

Sep. 2019 - Feb. 2021

Kangwon National University

B.S. IN DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER AND COMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING, GPA 3.86 / 4.5

Chuncheon, Republic of Korea

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2021

Experience ____

Riiid Seoul, Republic of Korea

NLP RESEARCH SCIENTIST Dec 2022 - Present

- Research on Large Language Model
- Research on Automatic Essay Assessment
- Research on Question Generation & Evaluation
- Data Analysis and Qualification for Procured Data

Netmarble Seoul, Republic of Korea

NLP RESEARCHER & ENGINEER Apr 2021 - Dec 2022

- · Maintenance on Game NMT Service
- · Research on Automatic Post-editing
- Research on Text-to-Speech Synthesis
- Development of Persona Chatbot
- Development of Chatbot with Passage Retrieval

Kakao Enterprise Seongnam, Republic of Korea

NLP RESEARCHER (RESEARCH INTERNSHIP)

Research on Aspect-based Sentiment Analysis using Self-supervised and Multi-task Learning

Konkuk University Seoul, Republic of Korea

STUDENT (ADVISOR: PROF. HARKSOO KIM)

· Research on Persona-based Chatbot

· Development of Korean Language Model

Kangwon National University

STUDENT (ADVISOR: PROF. HARKSOO KIM)

• Research on Persona-based Chatbot

Chuncheon, Republic of Korea

Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

Sep 2020 - Feb 2021

Mar 2020 - Sep 2020

Publications

INTERNATIONAL PUBLICATIONS

Multi-Architecture Multi-Expert Diffusion Models

Yunsung Lee*, Jin-Young Kim*, Hyojun Go*, Myeongho Jeong, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Seungtaek Choi

(*eaual contribution)

Arxiv Preprint (Under review)

Addressing Negative Transfer in Diffusion Models

Hyojun Go*, JinYoung Kim*, Yunsung Lee*, Seunghyun Lee, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Hyeongdon Moon, Seungtaek Choi

(*equal contribution)

NeurIPS 2023 (Accepted)

Evaluation of Question Generation Needs More References

<u>Shinhyeok Oh</u>*, Hyojun Go*, Hyeongdon Moon, Yunsung Lee, Myeongho Jeong, Hyun Seung Lee and Seungtaek Choi ACL 2023 (Findings)

(*equal contribution)

Cross Encoding As Augmentation: Towards Effective Educational Text Classification

Hyun Seung Lee*, Seungtaek Choi*, Yunsung Lee, Hyeongdon Moon, <u>Shinhyeok Oh</u>, Myeongho Jeong, Hyojun Go, Christian Wallraven

(*equal contribution)

ACL 2023 (Findings)

RWEN-TTS: Relation-aware Word Encoding Network for Natural Text-to-Speech Synthesis

<u>Shinhyeok Oh</u>*, HyeongRae Noh*, Yoonseok Hong, Insoo Oh

(*egual contribution)

AAAI 2023 (Oral Presentation)

Netmarble AI Center's WMT21 Automatic Post-Editing Shared Task Submission

Shinhyeok Oh*, Sion Jang*, Hu Xu*, Shounan An, Insoo Oh

(*equal contribution)

WMT @EMNLP 2021 (1st place)

Deep Context- and Relation-Aware Learning for Aspect-based Sentiment Analysis

 $\underline{\textbf{Shinhyeok Oh}}^*, \textit{Dongyub Lee}^*, \textit{Taesun Whang, IlNam Park, Gaeun Seo, EungGyun Kim, Harksoo Kim}$

(*equal contribution)

ACL 2021 (Oral Presentation)

Improving Document-Level Sentiment Classification Using Importance of Sentences

Gihyeon Choi, Shinhyeok Oh, Harksoo Kim

Entropy, 2020 (SCIE)

Multi-Turn Chatbot Based on Query-Context Attentions and Dual Wasserstein Generative Adversarial Networks

Jintae Kim, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Oh-Woog Kwon, Harksoo Kim

Appl. Sci., 2019 (SCIE)

DOMESTIC PUBLICATIONS

Method of Reflecting Various Personas in a Chatbot

Shinhyeok Oh, Seokwon Jung, Harksoo Kim

Journal of KIISE, 2021 (KCI)

Movie Revies Sentiment Analysis Considering the Order in which Sentiment Words Appear

HongJin Kim, Damrin Kim, Boeun Kim, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2020

Korean Named Entity Recognition Using ELECTRA and Label Attention Network

HongJin Kim, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2020

Korean Generative Chatbot using Topic Embedding

Shinhyeok Oh, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2020

Personal Characteristics Classifier for Persona Chatbot Research

<u>Shinhyeok Oh</u>, Harksoo Kim, Jeong-Eom Lee, Seona Kim, Youngmin Park, Myungho Noh

KSC 2019

Personalized Multi-Turn Chatbot Based on Dual WGAN

<u>Shinhyeok Oh</u>, Jintae Kim, Harksoo Kim, Jeong-Eom Lee, Seona Kim, Youngmin Park, Myungho Noh

HCLT 2019

Multi-head Attention and Pointer Network Based Syllables Dependency Parser

HongJin Kim, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Damrin Kim, Boeun Kim, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2019

Persona Reflection Method for Generative Chatbot System

<u>Shinhyeok Oh,</u> Jintae Kim, Youngmin Park, Seona Kim, Jeong-Eom Lee, Harksoo Kim

KCC 2019

Korean Dependency Parsing Using ELMo and Multi-head Attention

Seongsik Park, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Hongjin Kim, Sihyung Kim, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2018

Korean Dependency Parsing using Multi-head Attention and Pointer Network

Seongsik Park, **Shinhyeok Oh**, Hongjin Kim, Harksoo Kim

HCLT 2018

Honors & Awards

Nov 2021 **1st Place**, Automatic Post-Editing shared task @WMT, EMNLP 2021

Oct 2020 Special Prize, Korean Language Information Processing Competition - Chatbot @HCLT 2020

Oct 2020 Special Prize, Korean Language Information Processing Competition - Sentiment Analysis @HCLT 2020

Oct 2019 Bronze Prize, Korean Language Information Processing Competition - Dependency Parsing @HCLT 2019

Sep 2019 Gold Prize, Kangwon SW Festival - @National Program of Excellence in Software

Oct 2018 Grand Prize, Korean Language Information Processing Competition - Dependency Parsing @HCLT 2019

Jul 2016 1st Place, Department of Computer and Communications Engineering (Rank: 1/97), Spring Semester 2016

Certificate

Certificate of Engineer Information Processing

HUMAN RESOURCES DEVELOPMENT SERVICE OF KOREA

Republic of Korea

2019

Skills_

- Languages: Python, Java, C, C#, HTML/CSS/JS, Android
- Deep Learning Libs: PyTorch, Tensorflow
- Etc.: Springboot, Gnuboard, Google Cloud Platform

Teaching Experience

2023	Instructor	, Special Lecture for Freshmar	(AI Foundation Models)	@Kangwon National University
------	------------	--------------------------------	------------------------	------------------------------

2022 Instructor, Special Lecture for Junior (Career in Artificial Intelligence) @Kangwon National University

2020 **Teaching Assistant**, Natural Language Processing @LG Uplus

2018-2019 **Teaching Assistant**, Java Programming, C Programming, App Programing @Kangwon National University

2017 **Instructor**, Java Programming (Supplementary classes supported by Kangwon National University)

Republic of Korea Republic of Korea Republic of Korea Republic of Korea Republic of Korea

Academic Activities

- Reviewer of ACL, NAACL, EACL, and ARR
- Reviewer of IEEE Transactions on Audio, Speech and Language Processing